Guide to the Yale University Library Records Concerning Position Classification and Pay Plans
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Yale University Library records concerning position classification and pay plans
1926-1966
RU 806
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
(3 boxes)
T he records consist of reports, charts, statistical data, questionnaires, job descriptions, and work description sheets documenting position classifications, pay plans, and the trainee program at the Yale University Library.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-A (YRG 32-A), Central records of the Yale University Library and records of the librarian
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
T he records consist of reports, charts, statistical data, questionnaires, job descriptions, and work description sheets documenting position classifications, pay plans, and the trainee program at the Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
Academic librarians -- Salaries, pensions, etc.; Academic libraries; Librarians -- Job descriptions; Librarians -- Salaries, pensions, etc.; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. Library
- Records of the Yale University Librarian concerning position classification and pay plans, 1926-1962; Accession 19ND-A-236
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2038.
  Scope and Contents
  The material in this series is alphabetically arranged by subject. Within the large sections on other libraries' systems and work description sheets, the material is in alphabetical order by name of library or department.
  Included in this series are reports, forms, charts, statistical records, questionnaires, and miscellaneous types of material. Topics cover the American Library Association, class specification, job and merit analysis and rating, position classification, the trainee program, and work description sheets. At the end there is an Historical copy of Library Job Descriptions, in 2 vols.
  - American Library Association, 1945-1946 (Box 1)
  - Class specification and individual job summary sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Class specification, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Comments, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Comments, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comments, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Forms and procedure, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Job analysis survey, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Job rating, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Job requirements questionnaires, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Job requirements, 1946. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Merit ratings, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Merit ratings, 1947-1948, May-June (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Merit Ratings Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Other libraries' systems
    - Columbia University, 1944-1946 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Harvard University, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Library of Congress, 1946-1949 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Louisiana State University, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - New York Public Library, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Position classification
    - Personnel Assistant, Librarians Office, 1948-1955 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Stack Supervision, 1949-1950 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Librarian, German Literature Collection, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Revisions, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Staff Classification and Pay Plan Staff, 1946-1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Staff, Committee, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Staff, Committee Correspondence, 1946-1947 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Staff, Committee on Position, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Staff, Old File, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Staff, Position Designation, Charts, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Trainee Program (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Work description sheets, general
    - General
      - Position Analysis, to be filled, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Position Analysis, to be held, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Description of Positions, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Accession Department, Undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Binding Department, Undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Catalogue Department, Undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Circulation Department, Undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Historical Manuscripts Department, Undated (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Librarian's Office, Undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Linonia and Brothers, Undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Map Collection, Undated (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Photographic Department, Undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Rare Book Room, Undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Reference Department, Undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Reserve Book Room, Undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Serial Department, Undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Departmental Libraries, 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - General (Box 5)
      - Divinity School, working papers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
      - School of Fine Arts, working papers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
      - School of Forestry, working papers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - Law School, working papers, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - School of Medicine, working papers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - School of Music, working papers, Undated (Box 5, Folder 53)
      - Miscellaneous working papers, 1961-1962 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Historical copy of Library Job Descriptions, 2 vols. (Box 6)
  - Position Classification and Pay Plans, 1949-1966 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - PCPP Chronological File, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - PCPP Chronological File, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - PCPP Chronological File, 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - PCPP (revised November 1952) (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Grade Salary Range, Undated (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Exchanges Assistant, Accessions Dept. CSF-3, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Purchase Accessions Assistant CSF-3, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Questions -Equivalent Qualification, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Reactions and requests, 1941-1950 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - School libraries, 1948-1952 (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Working papers for L-9, revisions, 1955-1958 (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Supplement to the PCPP, 1954-1955 (Box 7, Folder 67)